# **ADHAM ALQATAWY**

+201090423828 | adhamelkatawy@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/adhamalqattawy | https://adhamalqatawy.github.io/Portfolio/

### SUMMARY

Experienced Data Analyst with 2 years of experience and SQL Instructor. My passion for data and eagerness to assist others in pursuing a career in this field are the driving forces behind my work. Passionate about simplifying processes, optimizing workflows, and solving problems to benefit teams and organizations. Committed to continuous learning and staying updated on industry advancements.

## EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst Dec 2021 – Present

Maxab, Egypt

- Building Data Models for the revenues team in Egypt and Morocco using dbt.
- Managed Morocco sales performance by conducting analysis, strategic planning, and ensuring precise execution for optimal results.
- Developed and maintained Routes script that generates daily routes for the on-ground teams. This
  helped the team to direct the visits to the needed retailers which improved the overall performance of
  the company.
- Developed a fraud detection model that identified and eliminated duplicate accounts, resulting in improving data accuracy and enabling healthy growth strategies.
- Developed and maintained Python scripts to automate routine tasks, saving 45 minutes of daily work and enhancing team productivity and daily operations.

#### Data Analysis Instructor

Sep 2022 – Nov 2023

Dotpy, Cairo

- Teach Data Analysis topics such as (SQL, Python, Excel)
- Provide 1:1 coaching session to help people solidify their knowledge about topics such as (SQL, Python)

#### EDUCATION

# **Higher Technological Institute**

2016 - 2021

BSc. Mechatronics Engineering

#### **Additional Courses**

Analytics Engineering Bootcamp, dbt Fundamentals, Udacity Data Analysis Nanodegree, Python for Everybody, Tableau 2020 A-Z, SQL for Data Analytics

#### SKILLS

**Database & Programming Languages:** SQL, Python, Data Warehouse, Data modeling, ETL & ELT **Software Tools:** dbt, Metabase, Tableau, Git & GitHub, Microsoft Excel, Snowflake, Jupyter Notebook **Leadership Skills:** Effective communication, Ability to teach and mentor, Decision maker, Problem solver.